Samuel Davidson

www.sambdavidson.com/ 1441 Forge Way, Draper, Utah 84020

Contact:

Mobile: (801) 833-3009

Email: samuel.bonnar.davidson@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuelbdavidson

Profile

Excited software engineer who enjoys collaborating with my team to find innovative solutions to complex programming challenges. I enjoy web and game development with friends in my free time.

Technical Expertise

Frameworks

NodeJS, AngularJS, RequireJS, Apache Maven, Apache Tomcat, Spring Frameworks, .NET MVC,
Web API, Entity Framework, Bootstrap, NUnit, Gherkin, Jasmine, Grunt.

Languages

• JS/TS, CSS, HTML, JAVA, C/C++, C#, SQL, XML, JSON

Software

• Visual Studio, Eclipse, JetBrains Tools, MS SQL Server, Azure, AWS, Git, Node, Grafana, Graphite, JIRA, Splunk, various deployment pipelines.

Work Experience

Expedia, INC - Software Engineering Intern

May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Interned on the package pricing team under the Expedia Worldwide Engineering department.
- Improved monitoring and metrics throughout multiple back-end services.
- Architected and implemented a new package pricing service use-case to better price certain travel packages and minimize unnecessary margin loss. Expected to result in a notable revenue increase in the following months.

DealerSocket - Associate Software Engineer

May 2015 – Feb 2016

- Architected a CRM platform in use by thousands of car dealerships globally.
- Developed in an Agile/Scrum environment with a high level of communication and collaboration between all team members.
- Front-end development on a SPA using AngularJS, RequireJS, and various Javascript libraries.
- Back-end development with HTML scraping and web shimming. (ExpressJS, NodeJS, cheerio)
- Improved server-side shim testing strategies with HTTP request mocking, significantly improving code coverage.

<u>Transfuels LLC</u> - Network Operations Technician

Fall 2014 - May 2015

• Fuel systems monitoring, security, and safety faults. Involved debugging embedded systems, transaction database analysis, and on-call troubleshooting.

Education

University of Utah

Graduating May 2017: Bachelors in Computer Science

- Software Practice in C#, Java, C/C++, Racket
- Computer Networking, Operating Systems, and Programming Language Design
- Strong understanding of algorithms, data structures, and various mathematics.

Hillcrest High School, Midvale, Utah

• International Baccalaureate (IB) Diploma and AP

Pluralsight Course Completions

• 30 courses including courses on pragmatic unit testing, data modeling, encapsulation and SOLID, and inversion of control. Full list: www.sambdavidson.com/pluralsight

Microsoft ASP.NET MVC Certified